Esmaeil Farhang

Senior Master Student

Phone: +989164481513

Website: https://esmaeilfarhang.github.io
Email: esmaeilfarhang@gmail.com

My education in Mathematics and AI and my experience as a Machine Learning R&D Engineer have provided me with a well-rounded background and enabled me to develop my research qualitative and analytical skills. I have the capability to resolve problems and implement solutions in research, which is confirmed through relevant Academic research and technical R&D experiences. In short, I am a hard-working and creative individual with a great passion for research in AI and related fields.

EDUCATION

University of Tehran, Iran

SEP 2017 - SEP 2020

Master of Science, Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence

Thesis: Effect of Spatial frequency content on the hierarchical object recognition **Advisors**: Dr.Mohammad Reza Abolghasemi Dehaghani & Dr. Babak Arabi

GPA: 17.00/20.00

Shiraz University, Iran

SEP 2011 - SEP 2106

Bachelor of Science, Major in Mathematics & Minor in Computer Science

FIELDS OF INTEREST

- Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- AI in Healthcare
- Machine Vision

- Data Science
- System and Computational Neuroscience
- Speech Processing

HONORS

• Ranked 37th among participants in the nationwide university entrance exam in the field of Computer Engineering (AI) and 46th in the field of computer science for a master's degree, Tehran, Iran. (2017)

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

• University of Tehran Cognitive Systems Lab (June 2018 - now)

Teaching Assistant

- Deep Learning with Applications, University of Tehran (Spring 2019 & 2020)
- Statistical inference, University of Tehran (Fall 2019)
- Pattern Recognition, University of Tehran (Fall 2018)

Our responsibilities included Designing homework and helping students with assignments, delivering the assignment, marking projects, and exams.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning R&D Engineer at HiBrainy (Roham AI)

July 2019 - July 2020

- Developing the TTS(Text to Speech) technology for English, French, and Persian and deploying services in the HiBrainy Platform (used novel deep learning methods).
- R&D on face anti-spoofing, liveness detection, head pose estimation, face depth estimation, and face emotion detection using novel deep learning methods

PUBLICATIONS

- Esmaeil F, Mohamad-Reza A, Babak A. Temporal Dynamic of Spatial Frequency Representation in IT Cortex. Poster presented at: 8'th Basic and Clinical Neuroscience Congress; 2019 December 18-20; Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran
- Under Preparation: Esmaeil F, Ramin T, Mohamad-Reza A, Babak A. Is Basic level advantage maintain in HSF and LSF?

LANGUAGES

English (prepare for TOEFL), Persian (Native), Turkish (Familiar), Arabic (Familiar)

PROGRAMING SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, C/C++, R
- Deep Learning Frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras
- Speech Recognition and Synthesis Toolkit: Kaldi, Espnet, Marytts, HTS
- Other Languages: Familiar with Java, Android, and Haskell Languages
- Linux / Git / Docker

SELECTED ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Deep Learning with Applications

Spring 2018

- Implementation Neural Network Combined with RNN and CNN and Use CTC loss for Librispeech data set for converting speech to text.
- Implementation parallel structure Gaussian mixture model -hidden Markov model (GMM-HMM) using the Viterbi and Boum-Welch algorithm, and compare with the gaussian mixture model Deep Neural Network (GMM DNN) on Spoken Arabic Digit Data Set

Cognitive Neuroscience

Spring 2019

- Implement a Behavioral and psychological task
- Brain Neural Data Analysis using machine learning tools

Pattern Recognition

Fall 2017

• Designing and implementation of traditional machine learning classifiers for different problems.

Reinforcement Learning

Fall 2017

• Implementation and comparison of different RL methods such as Q-Learning and SARSA in multi-state environments and Continuous RL methods such as RBF and Fuzzy

Social Networks

Fall 2018

Creating the relationship graph between the spiking activity of hundreds of neurons in mouse somatosensory cortex slice
cultures, using the transfer entropy, Granger causality, and cross-correlation methods and comparing these methods using
the social network analysis tools of python and Matlab

Data Analytics

Fall 2018

- Investigating the Variable of Social Trust and Comparing its Effective Factors on the Basis of a Survey on Iranian People From 1999 to 2009 for a descriptive Analytics Project with python.
- Predicting the Saccadic Targets with Individual and Population Neural Response for Predictive Analytics Project with python.

Statistical Inference

Spring 2018

• Analyzing and Visualizing the FIFA Player dataset with R

REFERENCE

DR. Mohammad Reza Abolghasemi Dehaghani

• Assistant professor - email: dehaqani@ut.ac.ir

Dr. Babak Nadjar Araabi

• Professor - email: araabi@ut.ac.ir